Finding Aid for the Akahori Family papers, ca. 1908-1965 LSC.2010.01
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Writings and publishing by Masaru
  - "Nichibei Shimbun" [characters] [Japanese American News]
    - "Ame ni kiku tabigokoro" [characters] [Wanderlust as heard through the rain], 1941 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      A series of essays Akahori wrote for the "Nichibei."
    - Records regarding the proposed publication of the "Zaibei nihonjin jinmei jiten" [characters] [Who's Who of Japanese in America], 1941 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Biographical data of Japanese families residing in the Pacific Northwest area for inclusion in the proposed publication of the "Zaibei nihonjin jinmei jiten" (1 of 6), 1941 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Includes data on approximately 500 families.
    - Biographical data of Japanese families residing in the Pacific Northwest area for inclusion in the proposed publication of the "Zaibei nihonjin jinmei jiten" (2 of 6), 1941 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Biographical data of Japanese families residing in the Pacific Northwest area for inclusion in the proposed publication of the "Zaibei nihonjin jinmei jiten" (3 of 6), 1941 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Biographical data of Japanese families residing in the Pacific Northwest area for inclusion in the proposed publication of the "Zaibei nihonjin jinmei jiten" (4 of 6), 1941 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Biographical data of Japanese families residing in the Pacific Northwest area for inclusion in the proposed publication of the "Zaibei nihonjin jinmei jiten" (5 of 6), 1941 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Biographical data of Japanese families residing in the Pacific Northwest area for inclusion in the proposed publication of the "Zaibei nihonjin jinmei jiten" (6 of 6), 1941 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - "Town Crier"
    - Lease agreements and licenses, 1946-1950 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - "Town Crier" business correspondence, 1947 January-1961 February (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Subscription list, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Advertisement contract records, 1950-1966 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Partial manuscript for "Kikashiken no tora no maki: shiminken no nijugokamuku" [characters] [Twenty-five lessons in citizenship], 1950 and 1952 (Box 17, Folder 12)
      A citizenship manual on American institutions to assist Issei to pass their naturalization examination. Edited by Akahori and published by the "Town Crier."
    - Print ad sample, 1946-1950 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Booklet of sample images, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Clippings of sample graphics, undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Press photographs, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Partially completed manuscript of "Zaibei nikkeijin jinmei jiten" [Directory of Japanese residing in the U.S.], 1954 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "Town Crier Year Book 1947: U.S. Japanese Address Book" (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - "Orphans All: Toyohiko Kagawa" by Ralph Ernest Downie, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      The Japanese translation and the original English section on Toyohiko Kagawa published in Ralph E. Downie's "Orphans All" (Seattle, 1936).
    - "Anata no unsei" [characters] [Your future] and "Nanka meibutsu Hyoroku goyomi" [characters] [Los Angeles Almanac], 1947 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      A pamphlet explaining the signs of the Zodiac (in English) and a pamphlet explaining the sexagenary cycle (in Japanese).
    - "Nihonkoku kempo" [characters] [Constitution of Japan], 1947 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      A mimeographed reproduction of the postwar Japanese Constitution. In Japanese and English.
    - "Go-meishi kokancho" [characters] [Trading book of business cards] (1948) (Box 18, Folder 7)
      Special new year issue for the purpose of printing the new year greetings of subscribers and advertisers. In English and Japanese.
    - "Go-meishi kokancho" [characters] [Trading book of business cards] (1949) (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - "Wakodo" [characters] [The Youth], No.2, 1950 July (Box 18, Folder 9)
      A literary magazine published by Inter-culture Club and printed by the "Town Crier." A collection of short essays, poems, and fiction written by Kibei and Japanese students in Los Angeles.
    - 2 issues of "Shinnengo" [characters] [Special New Year's issue] (1965&1966), 1965 and 1966 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      In English and Japanese
    - "Shinran Shonin shichi hyaku nenki" [characters] [The 700th Anniversary of the Death of Shinran, the Holy Priest], 1958 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - "Nanka nikkeijin eigyo annai" [characters] [Southern California Japanese Business Guide]1962-63, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - "Town Crier Blue Book 1948-1949: Our 2nd Year" (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - "Town Crier Blue Book 1949-1950: Our 3rd Year" (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - "Town Crier Blue Book 1951-1952: Our 4th Year" (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - "Town Crier Blue Book 1952-1953: Our 5th Year" (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - "Teien gafu" [characters] [Art of the Landscape Garden in Japan and in America] (Town Crier Blue Book), 1954 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - "Kokyo gyoen gafu" [characters] [Pictoral record of the Imperial gardens] (Town Crier Blue Book), 1954 and 1956 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - "This Is California: Early History of California and its Developments into a State" (Town Crier Blue Book 12 Year), 1959-1960 reprint of the original 1932 publication (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - "Town Crier Blue Book 1961: Our 15th Year" (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - "Town Crier Blue Book 1962" (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - "Nanka nihonjin yakyushi" [A History of Japanese Baseball in Southern California], undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Listings of the names and addresses of Japanese for the "Zenbei nihonjin jushoroku" [A Directory of the Japanese in America] (1 of 2), 1947 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      Compiled from the 1947 shinnengo furoku [New Year's special issues] of various Japanese newspapers, including Nichibei Jiji, Chicago Shimpo, Hokubei Shimpo, and Rafu Shimpo. Lists approximately 750 names in total.
    - Listings of the names and addresses of Japanese for the "Zenbei nihonjin jushoroku" [A Directory of the Japanese in America] (2 of 2), 1947 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Drafts for the "Town Crier" special publication of "Nichibei shuko hyakunensai gafu" [characters] [A Photo Album to Commemorate 100-Years of Japanese American Amity], 1960 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Manuscripts for the publication of "Nichibei shuko hyakunensai gafu" [characters] [Photo Album to Commemorate 100-Years of Japanese American Amity] (1 of 2), 1960 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Manuscripts for the publication of "Nichibei shuko hyakunensai gafu" [characters] [Photo Album to Commemorate 100-Years of Japanese American Amity] (2 of 2), 1960 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Corrected proof of "Nichibei shuko hyakunensai gafu" [characters] [Photo Album to Commemorate 100-Years of Japanese American Amity], 1960 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Printed copy of "Nichibei shuko hyakunensai gafu" [characters] [Photo Album to Commemorate 100-Years of Japanese American Amity], 1960 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Thank-you letters from the students of Takahi Elementary School of Hiroshima Prefecture for sending them copies of "Nichibei shuko hyakunensai gafu" [characters] [Photo Album to Commemorate 100-Years of Japanese American Amity], 1960 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - A few articles Masaru printed in the "Ofu Nippo" [characters] [Sacramento Daily News], "Kanada Shimbun" [characters] [Canada News], and "Nippon to Amerika" [characters] [Japan and America], ca.1940-1941 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Office records of Akahori Horitsu Jimusho
  In the prewar years, some bilingual Issei who had formal legal training or experiences in handling legal matters in the United States assisted other Issei with their legal affairs. They often opened a horitsu (legal) or tsuyaku jimusho (interpreter's office) to render such services such as writing business letters, preparing legal documents, acting as court interpreters, and referring court cases to American lawyers. Akahori ran such an establishment in Little Tokyo and Terminal Island, California, from 1924 to 1933. There, he provided legal assistance to numerous individuals in cases such as divorce, traffic accidents, and unpaid wages. A large portion of his clientele came from the fishing industry in Terminal Island. His office also functioned as a collection agency.
  - Correspondence with American lawyers, 1960 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Willard J. Laney, Attorney at Law, Los Angeles, 1929 September=1933 April
    - Correspondence with Lester O. Luce, Attorney at Law, Inglewood, 1929 May-1930 March
    - Correspondence with Stephen Monteleone, Attorney at Law, Los Angeles, 1929 December-1931 July
    - Correspondence with Tim Okawara, Attorney at Law, Fresno, 1931 October
    - Correspondence with Max Lewis, Attorney at Law, Los Angeles, 1932 April-1934 December
    - Correspondence with Arthur C. Webb, Attorney at Law, 1931 September-November
  - Correspondence with L.C. Crossman, Searcher of Titles, Los Angeles, 1931 November-1933 January (Box 21, Folder 7)
    Masaru often relied on Crossman's services to look up past court cases and related files.
  - Correspondence with R.J.H. Mittwer, notary public and Japanese interpreter, Los Angeles, 1931 February-1933 January (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence regarding delinquent balances of operation costs for the Akahori Horitsu Jimusho, 1932 March-July (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Scattered correspondence on various business dealings, 1927-1931 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence regarding political campaigns that Akahori supported, 1932 May-June (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence with Arch Colemen, First Assistant Postmaster General, Washington, 1933 March (Box 21, Folder 12)
    Regarding the request by residents of Terminal Island for the Terminal Island post office to retain its current station.
  - Records on clients who sought assistance in legal matters at the Akahori Horitsu Jimusho
    - Arai, Yoshitaro, 1929 July (Box 21, Folder 13)
      Regarding his immigration status or an employment application.
    - Dei, Eitaro, Long Beach, 1927 December-1931 October (Box 21, Folder 14)
      Regarding the transfer of a property title.
    - Fujikawa, Y., gardener, Los Angeles, 1930 April-October (Box 21, Folder 15)
      Regarding claims for unpaid wages filed with the Division of Labor Statistics and Law Enforcement.
    - Fujimoto, F.S. and Kato, G., 1929 September (Box 21, Folder 16)
      Regarding the issuance of their operator's licenses.
    - Goto, Noboru, fisherman, Terminal Island, 1931 June-1932 August (Box 21, Folder 17)
      Regarding the issuance of a Japanese Consulate residency certificate, required to secure employment on a fishing boat
    - Harada, K., West Los Angeles, 1930 July-1931 November (Box 21, Folder 18)
      Regarding the filing of a complaint for damages caused by an automobile accident.
    - Hayashi, Ayame, 1930 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Regarding her divorce, the selling of her florist business, and the buying of a chop suey restaurant.
    - Hayashi, Kenzo, insurance agent, Los Angeles, 1933 November-July (Box 22, Folder 2)
      Regarding the settlement of a dispute over rent arrears. Hayashi was a defendant in a civil suit.
    - Hayashi, Shigeru, Los Angeles, 1924 April and 1931 March (Box 22, Folder 3)
      Includes 2 legal documents.
    - Hinoki, J., Terminal Island, 1932 September and October (Box 22, Folder 4)
      Regarding the fulfillment of a promissory note agreement.
    - Hiraga, J.S., Terminal Island, 1933 July-August (Box 22, Folder 5)
      Regarding the arrears of a loan payment.
    - Hirata, Isao, proprietor of a boarding house and a pool hall, Oxnard, California, and Rockspring, Wyoming, 1923 October-1931 August (Box 22, Folder 6)
      Regarding the collection of a balance payment.
    - Horita, Koshiro, farmer, Stockton, 1932 October-1933 January (Box 22, Folder 7)
      Regarding the settlement of disputes over large debts incurred from business failure.
    - Ichiki, Kinzo, farmer, Stockton, 1930 April-June (Box 22, Folder 8)
      Regarding his deportation on charge of assisting his brother's illegal entry into the U.S.
    - Iriye, K., Terminal Island, 1932 December-1933 February (Box 22, Folder 9)
      Regarding a bond balance owed to him.
    - Ishima Kazuyoshi, Inglewood, 1931 October (Box 22, Folder 10)
      Regarding the custody of his son.
    - Ishino, Yuki, cafe manager, Terminal Island, 1933 February-March (Box 22, Folder 11)
      Regarding the unauthorized sale of liquor.
    - Izawa, Sokichi, barber, Hollywood, 1931 September (Box 22, Folder 12)
      Regarding application for a reentry permit.
    - Japanese Farmers Association of Los Angeles, 1928 December-1931 August (Box 22, Folder 13)
      Regarding the claims for unpaid wages filed by employees.
    - Kamidoi, 1930 August (Box 22, Folder 14)
      Regarding the adoption of Yone Tanada.
    - Kawano, K. (George Kono), restaurant proprietor, Los Angeles, 1929 October-1931 August (Box 22, Folder 15)
      Regarding the investigation into claims filed by the wife of his late business partner.
    - Kawashima, J., San Gabriel, 1930 April (Box 22, Folder 16)
      Regarding the sale of an estate.
    - Kiuchi, Sadaji, 1930 May (Box 22, Folder 17)
      Regarding his enrollment in school in the U.S.
    - Kochi, Y., candy maker, Los Angeles, 1932 July-1933 January (Box 22, Folder 18)
      Regarding the filing of claims for damages caused by a fire, and settling of personal disputes with another Japanese.
    - Kodama, Sotaro, Los Angeles, 1932 July-1933 January (Box 22, Folder 19)
      Regarding a suit he brought against a printer for stealing and selling his Japanese translation of the Operator's Examination.
    - Kogano, T., fisherman, Terminal Island, 1933 April (Box 22, Folder 20)
      Regarding his exemption from tax payments for a boat he previously owned.
    - Kojima, K., fisherman, San Pedro, 1932 June (Box 22, Folder 21)
      Regarding divorce.
    - Kojima, Yachio, Terminal Island, 1932 June (Box 22, Folder 22)
      Regarding the collection of an outstanding balance.
    - Koshino, J., ca.1927 (Box 22, Folder 23)
      Regarding the application for a reentry permit.
    - Maeda, K., pool hall operator, Los Angeles, 1929 January-May (Box 22, Folder 24)
      Regarding a police raid on the charge of illegal gambling on the premises of his operation.
    - Mambo, K., gardener, Hollywood, 1930 July-August (Box 22, Folder 25)
      Regarding a claim for unpaid wages file with the Division of Labor Statistics and Law Enforcement.
    - Maruki, Fuji, Downey, 1932 June-1933 May (Box 22, Folder 26)
      Regarding reissuance of a Japanese passport.
    - Masuno, Ryosaku, El Monte, 1929 (Box 22, Folder 27)
      Regarding his arrest.
    - Matsutsuyu, I., Terminal Island, 1929 December-1933 August (Box 22, Folder 28)
      Regarding the arrears of a mortgage payment.
    - Migaki, S., Los Angeles, 1929-1931 (Box 22, Folder 29)
      Regarding various payment settlements.
    - Minamiji, Fukutaro, hotel and pool hall operator, Terminal Island, 1932 April-1933 February (Box 22, Folder 30)
      Regarding the disposition of the estates of the late Minamiji Naoichi.
    - Mitsui family, undated (Box 22, Folder 31)
      Regarding the dissolution of partnership and subsequent financial settlement.
    - Mitsui, G. and Ozaki, M., restaurant operators, Los Angeles, 1930 August-1932 June (Box 22, Folder 32)
      Regarding the dissolution of partnership and the subsequent financial settlement.
    - Miyazaki, Goematsu, produce broker, Los Angeles, undated (Box 22, Folder 33)
      Regarding matters relating to the sale, repair, and operation of motor vehicles.
    - Mizukawa, T., gardener, Los Angeles, 1930 May-October (Box 22, Folder 34)
      Regarding a claim for unpaid wages filed with the Division of Labor Statistics and Law Enforcement.
    - Mori, Juhei, 1929-1930 (Box 22, Folder 35)
      Regarding a loan payment.
    - Morisawa, Ichitaro, fisherman, Terminal Island, 1932 November-1933 September (Box 23, Folder 1)
      Regarding the filing of claims for damages caused by automobile accidents and the cancellation of an automobile insurance policy due to payment arrears of premiums.
    - Muramatsu, Yozaburo, farmer, Hawthornes, ca.1928-1931 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      Regarding the collection of personal loans and a claim for damages caused by an automobile accident.
    - Muramoto, Shigeichi, 1936-1937 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      Regarding a fine.
    - Nagata, Tomoichi, fisherman, Terminal Island, 1933 February-August (Box 23, Folder 4)
      Regarding filing for bankruptcy.
    - Nagumo, Seiji gardener, Los Angeles, ca.1930 March-1931 August (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Nakamura, Harry T., cook, Los Angeles, 1930 January-May (Box 23, Folder 6)
      Regarding filing claims for unpaid wages with the Division of Labor Statistics and Law Enforcement.
    - Nakamura, Kitaro, fisherman, Terminal Island, 1932 October-1933 August (Box 23, Folder 7)
      Regarding arrears of a mortgage payment on a fishing boat.
    - Nakamura, Meiji, fisherman and vegetable-fruit stand vendor, Long Beach, 1932 May-December (Box 23, Folder 8)
      Regarding a lease agreement.
    - Nakamura, Nobutaro, 1933 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      Inquiry into the rental of a wharf.
    - Nakanishi, S., 1929 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      Regarding the payment of a rental.
    - Nakao, Shoichi, 1933 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      Regarding the investigation in an automobile collision.
    - Nakashima, K., 1937 (Box 23, Folder 12)
      Regarding the sublease of a storeroom.
    - Nakatsukasa, Setsuji, farmer, Redondo Beach, 1928 October-1932 December (Box 23, Folder 13)
      Regarding the entry of his brother and his wife into the U.S.
    - Nakayama, Munetaro, Hollywood, 1931 November-1932 September (Box 23, Folder 14)
      Regarding application for a reentry permit and the extension of the immigration bond due to a delayed departure.
    - Ogawa, Tsunesaburo, produce market employee, Los Angeles, ca.1927-1931 August (Box 23, Folder 15)
      Regarding divorce and claims for unpaid wages.
    - Okada, Nobuko, housewife, Los Angeles, 1931 April-November (Box 23, Folder 16)
      Regarding filing for divorce.
    - Okumura, Harry S., produce market proprietor, Los Angeles, 1931 March-1933 May (Box 23, Folder 17)
      Regarding small claims court cases and legal counseling on other miscellaneous matters.
    - Oyama, Jiro, 1929 (Box 23, Folder 18)
      Regarding the recovery of a life insurance claim.
    - Sasaki brothers (Kichiro and Shichiro), Buena Park, 1930 June-1931 August (Box 23, Folder 19)
      Regarding their eviction from the ranch by their Issei partner and restitution claims.
    - Sassa, S., 1928 (Box 23, Folder 20)
      Regarding the collection of a paymnet.
    - Shiraishi, Senyo, inmate of the state penitentiary at Represa, California, 1931 March-1933 February (Box 23, Folder 21)
      Regarding the petition for retrial and claims for his mining rights in Baja California, Mexico.
    - Sonoda, Heijiro, 1920 and 1934 (Box 23, Folder 22)
      Regarding the sale of a patent.
    - Sugi, Yoshio and Elizabeth Willard, Los Angeles, 1931 April-August (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Suzuki, Kanejiro, Terminal Island, 1932 December-1933 July (Box 23, Folder 24)
      Regarding legal counsel on various matters.
    - Takahashi, Eimatsu, cafe operator, Terminal Island, 1932 September-1933 April (Box 23, Folder 25)
      Regarding small claims court cases.
    - Takase, Harutoshi, 1930 February (Box 23, Folder 26)
      Power of Attorney
    - Takata, Arthur S., Los Angeles, 1931 December-1932 April (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Takeuchi, Otoichi, Terminal Island, 1931 December-1932 April (Box 23, Folder 28)
      Regarding a complaint filed to the Los Angeles Municipal Officer for an accident occurring on public grounds.
    - Takeuchi, Shobei and Yasu, Long Beach, 1933 January-July (Box 23, Folder 29)
      Regarding claims on the late Otozo Takeuchi's life insurance policy and the settlement of his debt.
    - Tamaki, N., owner of a rooming house, 1933 (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Tanaka, Shogo, farmer, Bellflower, 1928 September-1933 February (Box 23, Folder 31)
      Regarding settlement on claims filed against Tanaka for damages caused by automobile accidents.
    - Tanaka, Yaichi, parolee, Los Angeles, 1930 January-July (Box 23, Folder 32)
      Regarding filing monthly reports to the state parole officer on Tanaka's behalf.
    - Tateishi, Tachiro, gardener, West Los Angeles, 1931 November-1932 January (Box 23, Folder 33)
      Regarding the petition for a parole hearing for Tateishi who was charged with possession of a liquor manufacturing still.
    - The Tawadas (1 of 2), ca.1927-1933 (Box 23, Folder 34)
      Kikuzo Tawada and his son, Kenzo, had been engaged in many different business ventures in Pecos, Texas; Pueblo, Colorado; and Oxnard and Los Angeles, California from about 1911 to 1932. These included oil drilling, farming, produce broker, and shipper. Akahori assisted the family as business advisor, collection agent, and legal counselor from about 1927 to 1932.
    - The Tawadas (2 of 2), ca.1927-1933 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Teramoto, Tatsuzaburo and Nishino, K., Terminal Island, 1928 December-1933 June (Box 24, Folder 2)
      Regarding the petition for Teramoto's parole and legal counseling on business and financial matters.
    - Togo, Noboru, 1930 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      Regarding a loan agreement.
    - Toma, Tsurumatsu, 1933 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      Regarding business license permits.
    - Tomita, Masaki, Hawthorne, 1930 February (Box 24, Folder 5)
      Regarding claims for damages caused by an automobile accident.
    - Torii, Zennosuke, Los Angeles, 1929 January-1931 October (Box 24, Folder 6)
      Regarding the settlement of a claim filed against Torii for damages caused by an automobile accident/
    - Tosaki, Seiroku, 1930 June (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Tsuda, Yukusue, drug store employee, Los Angeles, 1929 September-October (Box 24, Folder 8)
      Regarding his application for a reentry permit to visit Canada.
    - Tsutsui, Rinzo, Los Angeles, 1930 July-1931 July (Box 24, Folder 9)
      Regarding the renunciation of Japanese citizenship of his six Nisei children.
    - Uchida, Tsutomu, 1931 (Box 24, Folder 10)
      Power of Attorney.
    - Wada, Kishino, Terminal Island, 1933 February (Box 24, Folder 11)
      Regarding the disposition of her late husband's estate.
    - Wada, T., 1928 (Box 24, Folder 12)
      Regarding a plea bargain.
    - Wakino, H., undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
      Regarding the immigration status of his family.
    - Watanabe, Toku, 1930 January (Box 24, Folder 14)
      Power of Attorney for the execution of a will.
    - Yamada, Tokumatsu, gardener, Hollywood, ca.1927-1931 April (Box 24, Folder 15)
      Regarding a mining claim in Mexico and a claim for damages caused by an automobile accident.
    - Yamaguchi, S., Los Angeles, 1929 April (Box 24, Folder 16)
      Affadavit.
    - Yamamoto, M., proprietor of a fish cake company, San Pedro, 1929 April (Box 24, Folder 17)
      Regarding the sale of his business and the subsequent settlement of financial claims.
    - Yamashita, Frank, cafe proprietor, San Pedro, 1933 January-February (Box 24, Folder 18)
      Regarding the settlement of claims filed by an injured customer.
    - Yarita, J., 1929 July-1930 December (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Yokoyama, R., cafe owner, 1932 (Box 24, Folder 20)
      Regarding the collection of unpaid bills
    - Yoshimura, Shuzo, sales clerk, San Diego, 1929 January-February (Box 24, Folder 21)
      Regarding a small claims court case.
    - Scattered records on various clients, 1926-1933 (Box 24, Folder 22)